# Julia Santos

**UX DESIGNER** 

jqs1995@outlook.com linkedin.com/in/ssantosjulia/ juliasantos.im

#### **PROFILE**

My journey into UX design is fueled by a passion for crafting interfaces that not only look good but also resonate deeply with users' needs and behaviours. Transitioning from a background in sales and marketing, I bring a unique perspective to design, blending business knowledge with creative problem-solving to deliver intuitive and impactful user experiences.

#### **SKILLS**

UX Design, UI Design, User Research, Information Architecture, Wireframing, Prototyping, Usability Testing, Figma

Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator,

## **PROJECTS**

#### UX/UI Designer, Researcher | HighKey app

July 2024, BRAINSTATION CAPSTONE

 I have gained hands-on experience with the end-to-end design process, including UX Research, data analysis, wireframing, UI Design, Prototyping and usability testing.

# UX Designer | Kijiji Industry project

June 2024, BRAINSTATION HACKATHON

- Collaboratively engineered an innovative industry solution within a rigorous 24-hour timeframe.
- Played a pivotal role in a multidisciplinary team, comprising software engineers, data scientists, and fellow UX designers.
- Our presentation and deliverables earned high praise from Kijiji partners, highlighting the solution's seamless integration with existing company tools and its user-friendly design for immediate implementation.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### BrainStation | Certificate, Product Management

Toronto, ON | September 2024 - Present

#### BrainStation | Diploma, User Experience Design

April 2024 - July 2024, Toronto, ON

## University of Franca | Graphic Design Undergraduate Diploma

2021 - 2023, Sao Paulo, Brazil

# Federal University of the State of Rio de Janeiro | Bachelor's degree, Environmental Science (Incomplete)

Jan 2017 - December 2017, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

# Estacio | Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Environmental Engineering Technology

Jan 2014 - December 2015, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Graphic Designer, Freelancer**

Toronto, Canada | Jan 2021- Present

## Cleaner, Freelancer

Toronto, Canada | Oct 2019 - Jan 2021

# Sales Consultant, Full-Time

Ainter Network - Sao Paulo, Brazil | 2018-2019

#### E-commerce Manager, Self-Employed

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil | 2012-2018

#### Prefeitura Municipal de Sapucaia, Environmental technician intern

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil | July 2015- Dec 2015